The Pentagon is gathering air power for
a massive attack on Iran, possibly with
the intent of regime change. The USS
Abraham Lincoln carrier strike group is
moving toward the Middle East. Patriot
and Thad air defense systems are being
deployed. Non-essential US personnel and
equipment are being pulled back from
exposed regional bases. and over three
dozen US tanker aircraft and heavy lift
transporters are heading there. The
planning phase is now giving way to
execution. Iran, meanwhile, is not
sitting idly by. Russian and Chinese
cargo aircraft have been making rounds
into the country, almost certainly
carrying arms and ammunition. Since mid
2025, Thran has been stockpiling arms,
specifically Chinese weapons. On paper,
Iran now fields top-notch air defenses,
including HQ9B missiles. In practice,
however, that advantage is brittle. Air
defense systems only work efficiently
when layered and integrated with other
systems. Iran doesn't have that. However
one looks at it, the fuse is now
burning. The Pentagon is just waiting
for the perfect time. Attack too soon
and Iranians will rally around the flag.
Attack too late and the US will miss the
momentum. Half measures won't do. This
is the hinge on which decades turn and
what happens next will outlive everyone
in the room. Conflicts between states
don't just play out on battlefields
anymore. They also take place online
through cyber attacks, surveillance, and
[music] digital disruptions. The
internet essentially becomes part of the
conflict itself. And for ordinary people
trying to follow events as they develop,
simply being online can expose [music]
far more data than intended. That's
where NordVPN comes in. It encrypts your
internet traffic, protects your
location, and helps shield your data
from prying eyes. features like threat
protection pro block malware trackers
[music] and malicious websites before
they load, while dark web monitor alerts
you if your personal information ever
appears in data leaks or underground
markets. If you want a safer way to
browse, go to nordvpn.com/caspionreport
[music]
or use the link in the description. It
comes with a 30-day money back
guarantee. So, if you don't find it very
useful, you can just get your money
back. Clicking that link helps support
this channel, but it also gets you an
extended subscription. You get the
2-year plan plus four extra months. It's
a good deal, and again, it helps support
the channel when you sign up. The link
is nordvpn.com/caspionreport.
Give it a try.
The deadly protests in Iran continue to
rage on, raising the prospects of US
military intervention. Internet
connectivity has been largely shut down
in the country since January 8th, which
makes it difficult to ascertain the
scale and scope of the situation. Even
so, the protests are just a pretext for
military action. Iranians in the streets
may certainly want democracy, but Trump
has no real concern for any of them
because ultimately this isn't about
promoting democracy or freedom. Trump's
rhetoric on Venezuela, Ukraine, and
Greenland shows exactly what he thinks
of the liberal rules-based order. Case
in point, the renewed American push to
bomb Iran again is not driven by a
sudden crisis, least of all the current
protests, but by unfinished business
from the last showdown. You see, the
first US attack on the Iranian nuclear
sites was not quite as successful.
Around 400 kg of 60% enriched uranium
were unaccounted for. The Iranians had
secretly relocated these months ago in
anticipation of an attack. If further
enriched to 90%, which is a relatively
easy process, the stockpile could
produce enough file core for nine
nuclear weapons. And as long as that
stockpile remains missing, as long as
Iran retains even the slightest ability
to build a bomb, the war is unfinished.
Diplomats in Thran have been trying to
prevent or at least postpone a US attack
by offering to restart negotiations with
the Trump administration. If Iran were
to offer substantial concessions on its
nuclear program and its missile program,
it would reduce the risk of US military
action. However, America's demands have
expanded since the last standoff. They
now include not only ending nuclear
enrichment and cutting back on missile
stockpiles, but also getting rid of the
enriched nuclear material they have and
stopping support for regional proxy
groups. Iran is not going to meet these
prerequisites. And so in the coming days
and weeks, the risk of an attack on Iran
will remain high. At Al- Udide air base
in Qatar, widely regarded as the largest
US military base in the region with
around 10,000 troops, non-essential
aircraft have been moved away. This
satellite imagery shows the situation on
the ground. The same pullback is seen at
Prince Sultan Air Base in Saudi Arabia.
You don't do this when a diplomatic
resolution is around the corner. You
clear them when you expect Iranian
missiles to hit that base. For instance,
al- Udid sits less than 300 kilometers
from Iran and Shahab 3 missiles can
reach it in just 4 minutes. The
evacuation of Al- Udid and other bases
is a sign that the battlefield is being
cleared for a major fight. However, the
first and foremost question to ask is
not what the Pentagon can do, but what
it seeks to achieve. Strategy must
precede action. Trump's objective
remains largely ambiguous. It ranges
from regime change through a coup or
popular uprising to pressuring Thran
into a new nuclear agreement. If the
objective is to destroy Iran's nuclear
sites and eliminate the unaccounted
enriched uranium, then the mission calls
for B2 bombers, which are the only
aircraft that can carry the GBU 57
bunker busters. If the endgame is regime
change, then the scope expands far
beyond that. So in the absence of
clearly defined goals, the use of
military force risks becoming an end in
itself.
[music]
Fresh off the heels of the US raid on
Venezuela, some are now speculating that
the US could do a regime change
operation by targeting key Iranian
leaders. The belief is that doing so
would destabilize Iran's political
hierarchy and compel remaining elements
to submit to American terms. However, an
exfiltration mission similar to the
operation that captured Maduro in
Karacas is unlikely. US helicopters
would need to refuel inside Iranian
territory due to the distance from
friendly airspace and the Persian Gulf.
Karaka sits close to the coast, whereas
Thran is tucked far away from the open
oceans. In fact, the need for refueling
is precisely what led to the failure of
Operation Eagle Claw in 1980, which
sought to rescue US embassy staff held
hostage during the Islamic Revolution.
So any overt military action against
Iran would most likely take the form of
assassination strikes. However, this
approach carries inherent risks. For
one, Iran is ideologically entrenched
deeply. So, any kinetic attack that
kills or removes a figure like the
supreme leader or a senior military
official would certainly create shock,
but it would also play into the Shia
Islam martyrdom culture and thereby
galvanize unity. What's more, taking out
the Supreme Leader, as much as a
symbolic figure he is, wouldn't trigger
the government's collapse. Iran's
political machine is highly
institutionalized, and the IRGC has a
contingency plan to move into position
and consolidate control over the
clerical security elite. Once the IRGC
takes power and de facto assumes
guardianship of the state, they would
then select a new supreme leader. So
assassinating Iran's top leader would
only create a short-term crisis while
rallying hardliners around the flag and
sparking a wider display of nationalism
and unity. Another important
consideration are the regional
parameters. Saudi Arabia, Turkey, Qatar,
and Kuwait will likely withhold airspace
access for an attack on Iran.
Understandably, Iranian retaliation
would target these countries and they
want no part in that. But at the same
time, this restricts America's options
to three approach vectors. The first
corridor is from the north. Flying in
from Europe, American B2 bombers could
cross international airspace over the
Black Sea and enter Georgia, Armenia,
and Azerbaijan. None of the Caucasian
states is likely to approve, but the US
could do it undetected anyway. After
hitting their targets, the B2 bombers
could then exit the battle space by
following the same route back or by
flying south through the Indian Ocean.
The problem with this route is that it
comes awfully close to Russian airspace,
and the Russians may be able to track
the B2 bombers and warn their Iranian
counterparts. So, it's a risky route.
The second corridor is through Israel,
Jordan, and Iraq. Most of the US tanker
aircraft and heavy lift transporters,
over three dozen of them, are headed
toward Jordan. So, this central route is
the most likely. Admittedly, the Iraqis
will withhold their airspace, but they
lack the capacity to detect and track
stealth aircraft. By using B2, F-22, and
F-35s, the US could move about this
route and strike at Iran undetected.
This is also the same route that was
used previously to attack Iran's nuclear
sites. It's tested. It works, but it's
also somewhat predictable. The third
corridor is through the Indian Ocean.
This one offers the most freedom of
movement, but also requires the most
logistical prep work. Having the USS
Abraham Lincoln carrier strike group in
precisely that area certainly helps.
This option is also the preferred choice
for regional nations because it
minimizes their exposure to Iranian
retaliatory strikes. What's more, by
going through the south, the US could
also use conventional bombers such as
B-52s, thereby bringing in much more
firepower. The weight of evidence
suggests that it could be a combination
of the central and southern corridors.
By the way, this video in no way
promotes war. This is a realistic
assessment based on cold, calculated
interests and needs without the huff and
puff of morals. This is what the
Americans would do because it benefits
them. In no shape or form do we advocate
for war. Trump may think differently,
however. If he presses on and focuses on
destroying Iran's nuclear sites, the
attack would remain relatively
contained. B2 bombers flying in and out
would be enough. However, if the
objective expands to regime change, then
the operation takes on an entirely
different nature.
If the United States decides to go for
regime change in Iran, it could target
IRGC infrastructure, command centers,
and paramilitary officials in hopes of
weakening the security forces
responsible for the crackdown. Doing so
would create a brief period of internal
disruption and uncertainty, but it
wouldn't trigger meaningful negotiations
or push Thran toward collapse. The
Iranians would move quickly to restore
operational control and replace fallen
commanders. That's what they did during
the 12-day war in June. During this
window of disruption, protesters may
take up arms and clashes with law
enforcement could become even more
violent, but it still wouldn't be enough
to pose an existential threat to the
government. only a wider sustained
campaign targeting Iran's military
infrastructure, security apparatus, and
political leadership over an extended
period of time. Think of weeks, if not
months, could threaten Theran's
survival. A one-off military strike
wouldn't achieve anything. But a
sustained campaign that degrades Iran's
military capabilities and disrupts its
security forces would create a power
vacuum within the IRGC. The remaining
elements could then be coerced into
negotiation and compliance. Iran's
response to all this would of course be
proportional to the level of damage
inflicted. In a low-level escalation,
Iran could carry out a telegraphed
limited attack, such as striking US
diplomatic or military targets in Iraq
or harassing commercial or military
ships in the Strait of Hormuz. The goal
would be to reestablish deterrence while
avoiding a wider war. A mid-level
response could involve Iran launching
similarly telegraphed strikes against US
military assets in the Gulf, including
those in Saudi Arabia, Qatar, Kuwait,
and so on. Such a response, however,
would instantly raise the risk of
regional conflict. Finally, Iran's
leadership could go for a highlevel
escalation. While unlikely, this option
could see an unannounced Iranian attack
on American or Israeli targets or an
attempt to block the straight of Hormuz.
This would most certainly lead to total
war, but it would only happen if Tehran
truly believed the United States
threatened its survival. So, there are
degrees of escalation and both America
and Iran will try to hold their punches
so long as the other does the same.
Meanwhile, Israel could join the
American attack and go all out, but
their core mission will be entirely
different. Should the US attack succeed
and help topple the government, within
an hour of the handover of authority,
Israeli jets will attack and obliterate
Iran's military infrastructure.
So at the fleeting moment of hope, while
Iranians celebrate the revolution and
the military command is in disarray,
Israeli jets will make short work of
Iran's air defenses, missile launchers,
drone factories, etc. Israel will take
out everything regardless of whether the
new government is friendly or not.
Within hours, Iran will lose two decades
of military buildup. That's what they
did in Syria in the aftermath of Assad's
exit. And that's what they'll do in
Iran. So, Israeli jets will be armed,
fueled, and ready for precisely that
operational window. This killing blow
would not only decimate Iran's military,
but also paralyze the new government to
such a degree that it would be incapable
of mounting a geopolitical comeback.
That's the arithmetic of strategy. While
conflict produces casualties and
exhausts resources, it's often the
spectators who inherit the spoils.
I've been your host Shivan from Caspian
Report. If you approve of what we do,
please leave a comment, hit the like
button, and mayhaps share the video. In
any case, thank you for your time and s